## **Emilia Williamson**

# Full-Stack Developer

Midlands, UK ❖ Portfolio ❖ GitHub ❖ LinkedIn

A puzzle addict since childhood, nothing brought me more joy than making terrible websites with table layouts during the '00s. Fifteen years later, I quit my full time Parliament job to revisit that love of coding and pursue a career where I can apply my logical problem-solving skills. I have loved every second of my bootcamp journey and I'm excited to learn more as a developer.

## **SKILLS**

Full Stack Development: JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, React, Next.js, HTML, CSS, Tailwind Tools & Project: Git, Github, Postman, Figma, Pair Programming, Project Management, Agile, Scrum, Disney Room Ideation Testing: Jest, SuperTest, React Testing Library, Cypress, Test Driven Development, Red-Green-Refactor Interested in/Currently Learning: MongoDB, Firebase, AWS, Java, Golang, Python, Data Science, Data Architecture

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

School of Code

September 2022 - Present

Remote, UK

Bootcamper

- Developed full-stack JS applications using a range of tech, including Node, Express, React, and PostgreSQL
- Participated in pair programming, improving team-working, communication, and collaborative problem-solving skills
- Presented weekly hackathons and research tasks, explaining blockers and complex coding decisions to the cohort
- Exchanged continuous feedback with peers, practising resilience and cultivating a self-improvement growth mindset
- Implemented development best practices e.g. source control, documentation, accessibility and semantic variable naming
- Provided after-hours assistance to peers with programming fundamentals, solidifying my own personal technical skills
- Collaborated in agile teams to ideate, design, build and iterate on full-stack applications, using agile methodologies
- Demoed our final group project in a dynamic, high-pressure, exhibition-style event for employer partners

**House of Commons** 

**June 2017 - September 2022** 

Caseworker
Managed a high volume of casework enquiries, providing advice, guidance, support and advocacy to constituents

- Collaborated and negotiated with various stakeholders, including ministers and local authorities, to resolve complex issues
- Tailored delivery of information to ensure constituents' understanding and provided ad-hoc support as needed
- Boosted community engagement through press releases and social media posts drafted under tight deadlines
- Demonstrated strong leadership and mentorship skills by fully training four new members of the full-time staff

## **EDUCATION**

**University of Law** 

**September 2015 - July 2016** 

Birmingham, UK

Mooting, Business Challenge, Law Society Intervention Scheme

**Sheffield Hallam University** *BA Hons English – First Class* 

Graduate Diploma in Law - Commendation

**September 2012 - July 2015** 

Sheffield, UK

Class Representative (all 3 years), Creative Filmmakers Society, Archery Society, Final Project Mark: 85

## **PROJECTS**

LetChat

January 2023 - Present

A communication platform and information hub for landlords and tenants

GitHub repo | Live deployment

- Implemented NextJS server-side rendering and image optimisation for enhanced performance and speed
- Designed a team manifesto, code style guide & Git branching strategy to streamline work & prevent conflicts
- Presented and demoed the app to stakeholders and potential employers in a high-pressure environment

## **Insight Dashboard**

November 2022

A wellbeing app to ensure bootcampers are keeping up good habits

GitHub repo | Live deployment

- Led the recovery of the project following a major setback, staying agile and scaling back the MVP to deliver a product
- Stored and updated data on the front-end using React state variables, recovering time and improving efficiency